<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lucía Ferro</title>
    <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lucía Ferro</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>gl-es</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://luciaferro.es/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Is Jesus a fictional character?</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/is_jesus_fictional/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/is_jesus_fictional/</guid>
      <description>How much useful ancient knowledge have we lost? I am well aware of the sorrow that emerges from a belief crashing inside you. Cognitive dissonance is one of the most unpleasant experiences for the human mind. For the human body, even. Hopefully, this article won&amp;rsquo;t create any pain for anyone, though I have the feeling it will certainly itch.
Parisian Church by the author &amp;ldquo;Emperor Constantine, in the year 303, assembled a small redaction team and commissioned them to write the four Gospel and several other texts, all of them falsified, in order to implant his new religion throughout the Roman Empire, Christianity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It’s Monday</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/its_monday/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/its_monday/</guid>
      <description>A poem that, in my head, it&amp;rsquo;s jazz Photo taken by Lucia Ferro It’s Monday,
and you’re already done.
It’s Monday,
and you’ve had enough.
Four days
seem too much,
but you don&amp;rsquo;t know
what would they hide.
A shiny cold day
or a pleasant lunch.
It&amp;rsquo;s Monday,
what a bad start.
You&amp;rsquo;ve judged the week
before you&amp;rsquo;ve tried
to look for moments
that make worthy lifes.
They turn dark clouds</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The original Samhain and why the celebration of Halloween is more meaningful than ever</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/the_original_samhain_why_the_celebration_-halloween/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/the_original_samhain_why_the_celebration_-halloween/</guid>
      <description>About earth and spirit Photo by freestocks on Unsplash Today is the 31st of October, you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of it as Halloween, and you possibly consider it the Night of the Witches. You may think of it as spells, pumpkins and candy, but its origins have little to do with it.
Origin Photo by K. Mitch Hodge on Unsplash Everything started in Europe, precisely in the Celtic nations. The tradition originates in the druid festivity of Samhain, which actually didn&amp;rsquo;t have a specific date but was celebrated around the 5th-7th of November.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>World Anxiety</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/world_anxiety/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/world_anxiety/</guid>
      <description>A new perspective on an old concept The Netherlands. Photo taken by Lucía Ferro. The world feels big.
Big like the desert when you just leave the oasis.
Chaos burns full of entropy
like the skin of my feet
stepping on boiling sand bathed with dry heat.
I cannot bare any more
the details of this reality.
I want to be drowsy and bored
with some soothing fantasy.
But this strong and wild and feverish curiosity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The fine line to madness is being drawn in ICU</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/the_fine_line_to_madness_is_being_drawn_in_icu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/the_fine_line_to_madness_is_being_drawn_in_icu/</guid>
      <description>Delirium, the final frontier Source: Lame Digital Art done by the author Have you ever been so confused that you are simultaneously certain of your senses and losing your mind?
Maybe you had Covid-19 and thought you were about to cross to the other side.
Maybe one night, you were running a fever, and that veil between imagination and reality slowly faded away until you fell into a spiral of very uncomfortable feelings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confused in a sense</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/confused_in_a_sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/confused_in_a_sense/</guid>
      <description>A poem about friendship Photo: Switzerland&amp;rsquo;s air by Lucía Ferro I was feeling numb when they came.
No emotions or a flame.
They started to chat,
and I listen to them.
There was no anger
in what they said.
No envy, no revenge.
I was confused in a sense.
Why didn&amp;rsquo;t they complain?
Life isn&amp;rsquo;t fair,
and everybody feels some pain.
Later I came to learn
that all those bloody blades,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blonde: not a biopic but an insight into mental health</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/blonde_not_a_biopic_but_an_insight_into_mental_health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/blonde_not_a_biopic_but_an_insight_into_mental_health/</guid>
      <description>She was everywhere but seen nowhere Last night I watched Blonde, the movie about Marilyn Monroe. I will not tell you about the director or the novel is based on. I will tell you about the shadow this film leaves behind.
The narrative delivers the story in drops. These are powerful and have intense effects on your consciousness. We are talking about a story that, even though its scenes might not be totally real, is definitely accurate regarding feelings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Weak In The Sky</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/the_weak_in_the_sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/the_weak_in_the_sky/</guid>
      <description>A poem about compassion Switzerland, photo taken by the author We think we are brilliant
when we see others’ wrong side.
We treat them rough;
we ignore their shine.
As if life wasn’t hard enough,
we forget to note when they’re right.
And that’s what we’ve become:
Judges of the weak and fragile.
We feel strong and tough.
We forget our own troubled times
without which we wouldn’t have seen the light.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three life-lessons from a successful outcast</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/three_lifelessons_from_a_successful_outcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/three_lifelessons_from_a_successful_outcast/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever thought that the president of a country, instead of living like the richest 1%, should live like the rest of the population? You are not the only one. And it seems like a utopia, but no. It is possible and not a crazy idea after all. A Prime Minister once refused to live in the presidential residence and donated most of his salary to charity because &amp;ldquo;I earn more than I need&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sweat and fluids</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/sweat_and_fluids/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/sweat_and_fluids/</guid>
      <description>Machines creating wonderful things Photo by Compare Fibre on Unsplash We look at this piece of meat
like a bunch of iron hinges, wood and wheels.
We don&amp;rsquo;t see a body.
Instead, we see a machine.
We misuse it
letting our blood run free.
Our sweat.
Our fluids.
We perceive them as waste.
We even feel ashamed.
As if they were a sign of our character weakening.
Why do we so often forget</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Globalization: sometimes good, sometimes shit</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/globalization_sometimes_good_sometimes_shit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/globalization_sometimes_good_sometimes_shit/</guid>
      <description>Where we put the focus, we put our future This is the third piece of a series of articles that explore the effects of a specialized economic system in our society from a worldwide outlook. Here you can find previous articles:
Why specialization matters in our society: About growth and scarcity Link
The environmental and political impact of specialization in our society: The worth of a human being Link
Photo by Anne Nygård on Unsplash We are witnessing social fights that don&amp;rsquo;t seem possible to be solved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The environmental and political impact of specialization in our society</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/the_environmental_and_political_impact_of_specialization_in_our_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/the_environmental_and_political_impact_of_specialization_in_our_society/</guid>
      <description>The worth of a human being This is the second piece of a series of articles that explore the effects of a specialized economic system in our society from a worldwide outlook.
Why specialization matters in our society: About growth and scarcity Link
Due to market competition, our current socioeconomic system based on specialization encourages workers to get very good at one task or a few tasks rather than be mediocre at many tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gems and Weeds</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/gems_weeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/gems_weeds/</guid>
      <description>A poem to patience in friendship Photo by Lucía Ferro Don&amp;rsquo;t you dare break into my soul
looking for gems that can be sold
to warm yourself up when it&amp;rsquo;s cold
and forget about me when you find a clear road.
Indeed, I do set a high prize
for those who want to see my inside,
but you have to understand
so many times has it been vandalized!
that loneliness feels safer than being advised</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why specialization matters in our society</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/why_specialization_matters_in_our_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/why_specialization_matters_in_our_society/</guid>
      <description>About growth and scarcity This is the first piece of a series of articles that will explore the effects of a specialized economic system in our society from a worldwide outlook.
Photo by Christopher Burns on Unsplash It&amp;rsquo;s no surprise if I say that our society is profoundly polarised. It&amp;rsquo;s enough to put one newspaper next to the other and see how the same story has two very different approaches, even though journalism is supposed to be a discipline based on objectivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to spare</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/time_to_spare/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/time_to_spare/</guid>
      <description>A poem fueled with indignation Photo by Andrik Langfield on Unsplash I feel judged by the lot
when I am trying to be more.
More of myself.
More of the woman I left
behind when I was surviving,
and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have time for thriving.
But now I do.
I revise my behaviour and my childhood
and I find terrible things,
but sometimes, I also find it.
My authenticity.
So why do they judge me?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why a woman would play in a team with only men?</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/why_a_woman_would_play_with_men/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/why_a_woman_would_play_with_men/</guid>
      <description>Four years ago my husband got invited to join a football group for amateurs. He doesn&amp;rsquo;t like sports and he particularly hates football. He &amp;ldquo;sent&amp;rdquo; me instead. Photo by Donnycocacola on Unsplash I started playing indoor football when I was seven years old as an extra-curriculum activity I didn&amp;rsquo;t choose. My sister wanted to join and I didn&amp;rsquo;t like the idea of being alone with my parents. Of all things I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to choose in my childhood (there is a lot of them), this one actually turned out to be good later in life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You grew just like them</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/you_grew_just_like_them/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/you_grew_just_like_them/</guid>
      <description>A poem with disappointment Photo by Enrico Da Prato on Unsplash You, with me, were there
when the monsters yelled.
Under the sheets
hiding from darkness and scared,
you and I, trembling through a nightmare.
You talked about dreams so I would forget
we were children living in hell.
It didn&amp;rsquo;t feel safe, but I wasn&amp;rsquo;t alone,
or so I thought
until time made you grow.
You grew bigger, not wiser; I realised</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear customers, here is another step backwards after losing your right to repair</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/your_right_to_repair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/your_right_to_repair/</guid>
      <description>The frustration of replacing your electronic devices every little time. Photo by Jonas Leupe on Unsplash Our Smart TV Stick (not a brand) stopped functioning after a year of good use. No more warranty, unfortunately. An update of the software was advised and that&amp;rsquo;s what we did. If anything, worse!
WTF?
My husband and I don&amp;rsquo;t enjoy &amp;ldquo;luxury&amp;rdquo; that much. When we buy something we are happy with &amp;ldquo;good enough&amp;rdquo; stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFTs: Art and money. What you need to know to understand its meaning in our future society.</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/nfts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/nfts/</guid>
      <description>If it is such a great idea, why is it failing? NFT sales dropped by 92%, and nobody is actually surprised. Photo by Zach Key on Unsplash I recently watched a TEDx Talk by the Spanish philosopher Fernando Castro about crypto art and the situation of modern art. This video made me start a conversation about NFTs with my husband that evening, who is a software engineer and a videogame developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why America won&#39;t be able to protect their children without better public services</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/why_america_wont_be_able_to_protect_their_children_without_better_public_services/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/why_america_wont_be_able_to_protect_their_children_without_better_public_services/</guid>
      <description>Public services are the way out of a traumatic childhood Photo by Tadeusz Lakota on Unsplash Last year I decided to break the circle of my family trauma. I used to live by the assumption that there was no way out of my suffering but now I know I was already walking the necessary steps. Steps that were there thanks to the public services.
I was born in Spain (Europe), and I think that had a lot to do with the fact that I managed to survive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My fear of being alone</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/my_fear_of_being_alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/my_fear_of_being_alone/</guid>
      <description>Maybe not that story you are thinking about Photo by Greg Rakozy on Unsplash I met my husband when I was seventeen. I had lost my mother to breast cancer right a year before that. She gave me a scary childhood because she refused to leave my father to kill himself with alcohol. She told me she needed my father because she didn’t want to be alone once I had gone to college.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One step further, one step closer to yourself</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/one_step_further_one_step_closer_to_yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/one_step_further_one_step_closer_to_yourself/</guid>
      <description>These little things make the path to recovery. Photo by Lucía Ferro I am trying really hard to recover from my mental illness. I start to tell people that I have one, for instance. But the improvements come slowly.
I recently discovered a fascinating and ironic behaviour of mine. I always had the guts to go out and do whatever had to be done. I was brave and willing, even if it was scary, dangerous or laborious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>She deserves to feel safe</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/she_deserves_to_feel_safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/she_deserves_to_feel_safe/</guid>
      <description>I can only have a sense of security if… Photo by Joshua Rawson-Harris on Unsplash Last weekend my husband and I met another couple for dinner. The guy is always willing to help, and the girl has “empowering people” as her life purpose. Now and then, we eat together and we play a board game. During this time, we talk about plenty of things: the weather, feminism, movies, capitalism, bitcoin, work…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My mother was obsessed with building a house that I could inherit, but now, I can’t stand a minute being there</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/my_mother_obsessed_building_house/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/my_mother_obsessed_building_house/</guid>
      <description>How trauma changes everything Photo by Peter Herrmann on Unsplash When I was born, my whole family (9 people) were living in an old rented house. Just too many. The space was so reduced that my sister and I even had to share a room with our parents. So, naturally, my mother wanted to give us a better life, a home of our own.
My parents were hardworking people so, eventually, they managed to build the structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fatphobia didn’t exist until…</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/fatphobiadidnt_exist_until/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/fatphobiadidnt_exist_until/</guid>
      <description>You don’t know until you understand. Photo by David Hofmann on Unsplash All these new phobia words… are they really necessary? Here are my path and my findings.
I learned how to cook at a very young age. I didn’t have much access to processed food, so I grew up knowing what real fooders nowadays learn on Instagram. I also saw how important it was for my grandfather to lose weight to get a surgery done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The benefits of uberizing healthcare cover a dark reality.</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/uberizing_healthcare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/uberizing_healthcare/</guid>
      <description>SUBTITULO Photo by Alexander Sinn on Unsplash The future is here but unfortunately is not Stark Trek’s future, not yet in any case. We don’t have superintelligent machines that, with a simple scanner, can identify the smallest issue in our body or mind. Instead, we have quite a fancy AI doing some part of the diagnosis job. Not too bad, though. But the rest, all the difficult decisions, data collection, and leverage, still falls under a professional’s responsibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awakening to breath</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/awakening_breath/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/awakening_breath/</guid>
      <description>The Dark Night Of The Soul Eindhoven by Lucía Ferro I see myself
over and over
at the bottom
of a well.
The water
keeps raising.
My chest
keeps aching.
I take
my last breath
and the water
covers my head.
But the air
I exhale
creates a bubble
of pain.
And I feed
on the pain,
becoming the fuel
of my internal duel.
Oh, the fight
it elevates me high</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are we witnessing a behavioural sink?</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/are_we_witnessing_a_behavioural_sink/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/are_we_witnessing_a_behavioural_sink/</guid>
      <description>One too many We are 7,794,798,739 people on this planet and a few more astronauts out there. A significant portion of the population already lives in poverty, and the rest is going that way. We have a pandemic that we are struggling to control, and new generations seem to have little hope about their future. We can say that we have reached a point where decisions have to be taken. At least, we, humans, have the ability to assess, discuss and act upon survival situations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Errors make us human, and funny</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/errors_make_us_human_and_funny/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/errors_make_us_human_and_funny/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t like being wrong. I guess that&amp;rsquo;s something you and I have in common. In fact, very few people like it (the ones they like it, they are usually funny). Mistakes are the fuel that brings our minds closer to the truth, but they hurt really bad, so we try to avoid them. Some chosen ones find in mistakes something beautiful, and it is when they can use them as raw material for jokes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spain finally legalizes euthanasia</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/spain_finally_legalizes_euthanasia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/spain_finally_legalizes_euthanasia/</guid>
      <description>On the 17th of December, the Spanish government reviewed and approved the proposal of law on euthanasia. Within the Congress of Deputies, not everybody was a supporter, but general surveys say that most Spanish people were in favour of it. What does euthanasia mean? Euthanasia is the practice of intentionally ending a life to relieve chronic pain and unbearable suffering. Up to this point, only The Netherlands, Belgium, Colombia, Luxemburg and Canada have laws to regulate this kind of practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What nursing and prostitution have in common?</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/what_nursing_prostitution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/what_nursing_prostitution/</guid>
      <description>First of all, I am going to speak about these two subjects from a European point of view since I am Spanish and I have lived in different EU countries. I wanted to clarify this because I understand that both jobs are seen in very different ways depending on your origin and experiences. I am also going to identify myself with a feminist and I am going to happily hear other opinions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I can&#39;t stop listening to David Gilmour</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/david_gilmour/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/david_gilmour/</guid>
      <description>The Power of Music In fact, I am listening to him right now. It’s not addiction because, according to the American Psychiatry Association, addiction is a brain disease that is manifested by compulsive substance use despite harmful consequences and, even though I do feel drawn to his music, I don’t experience any harmful consequences. For that matter, I have found wellness.
I&amp;rsquo;ll explain. Sometimes, after I have written a post, I enjoy adding at the end of it a link to just one song.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What makes us humans doesn’t makes us hunters</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/what_makes_us_humans_doesnt_makes_us_hunters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/what_makes_us_humans_doesnt_makes_us_hunters/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t have a picture of a wild pig so here you&amp;rsquo;ve got a picture of a cute dog. It’s almost midday. A group of men arrives to the settlement carrying a wild pig dripping in blood. A few children welcome them amazed by the large hunt. Deeper into the settlement a woman prepares the fire. They know: Today it’s a feast day.
We often think about ourselves, humans, as aggressive, natural killers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The good and the bad marriage: is it really a matter of perspective?</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/the_good_and_the_bad_marriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 17:06:15 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/posts/the_good_and_the_bad_marriage/</guid>
      <description>There are so many versions of marriage that I had to make up my own. I was 25 years old when I got married to my high school sweetheart. At the time I thought I was too young to tie up myself for life. But I did it anyway because I had no doubts about my relationship. Some people told me that it was a good age to have kids, so I was doing the right thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One day at a time</title>
      <link>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/one_day_at_a_time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luciaferro.es/en/poems/one_day_at_a_time/</guid>
      <description>A poem about the past Photo: Simple wild life by Lucía Ferro I woke up
tired from last night.
The breakfast doesn&amp;rsquo;t go down
through my irritated gut.
I am nauseous.
I throw up,
ready for the bus
to pick me up.
I sit alone.
I don&amp;rsquo;t want to chat.
I want to sleep but
I have things to think about.
Today the bully will strike,
and no one will hear me shout,</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
